Travis Tincher

Software Engineer and Developer

Houston, TX (903) 574-1520 <u>trtincher12@gmail.com</u>

SKILLS

HTML5 | CSS | JavaScript| ES6 | Ruby | ReactJS | React-Native | NodeJS | JSON |
Express | MongoDB | Mongoose | Ruby on Rails | Redux | Git | Github | RESTful API |
Axios | SCRUM | Agile | SASS | jQuery | MERN | PostgreSQL | Heroku | Postman |
BCrypt | Bootstrap | Bulma | Adobe Photoshop | Adobe Illustrator

SUMMARY

I'm an innovative software engineer who builds user forward websites with a mobile first mindset and a passion for integrating function and design! My diverse background in philosophy, theology, and brewing have given me excellent critical thinking skills, great teamwork experience, and exceptional communication expertise.

PROJECTS

Houston CycleFix — https://houstoncyclefix.com/

- A mobile first responsive web application implementing automated booking for mobile bicycle repair/maintenance/building.
- Created an 80% greater efficiency in workflow for the owner so he could spend more time working and less time with booking and emailing prospective customers.
- Employs an inline Calendly widget which powers auto booking, and serves as CMS. This solution allowed the owner %100 customizability and flexibility with his schedule.
- Applies EmailJS to power custom contact form. This allows for a highly personalized user experience.
- Uses React/CSS/Sass/HTML5 to create views
- Utilizes **GitHub** for **version control** and branch testing before implementation.

myBallot WA — https://github.com/trtincher/myBallot

- A mobile first responsive web application ballot builder created to simplify and streamline the voting process for voters in Washington State.
- Earned 1st place in General Assembly's Alumni Social Impact Hackathon in a three-day sprint on a team of three UX/UI Designers and four Software Engineers.
- Uses React/CSS/Sass/HTML5 to create views, and Consumes voterwa API
- Utilizes GitHub for version control and branch testing before implementation.

Brewery mApp — https://github.com/trtincher/Brewery-mApp

- A **mobile first responsive web application** that enables the user to create a custom interactive map of their brewery experiences.
- Used React/Bootstrap/HTML5 to create views and consumed API from https://www.openbrewerydb.org/.
- Utilized **GitHub** for **version control** and branch testing before implementation on the master branch.

Forte — https://github.com/trtincher/P3-GroupLab-Frontend

- Built backend with Express/Mongoose/MongoDB to create related teacher and student models with full CRUD functionality. Used HTML5/SCSS/React/Axios to create the views.
- Utilized **GitHub** for **version control** and remote team organization. Team members used branches and pull requests to the main branch to maintain an orderly project workflow.

EXPERIENCE

Ctrl Alt Elite, Houston — *Software Engineer (Freelance)* SEPTEMBER 2020 – PRESENT

 Implementing intuitive user experience designs and building fully functioning front-end and full-stack responsive web applications with a cross-collaborative team of designers and software engineers.

Saint Arnold Brewing Co., Houston — *Brewer/Bartender* MARCH 2018 – December 2019

Responsible for brewing, fermentation, and filtration of beer.
 Additionally, for all cellar cleaning and sanitizing duties, and serving on the sensory panel for continual quality control.

Whole Foods Market, Houston — Baker

MARCH 2018 – December 2019

• Baked all goods for the bakery and provided customer service.

Barnes & Noble, Inc., Houston — Online Order Processing Supervisor MARCH 2018 — December 2019

 Manage and organize online orders for all 9 HCC bookstore locations. Supervise online order personnel. Provide customer service

EDUCATION

General Assembly - Remote

Software Engineering and Development MAY 2020 – AUGUST 2020

Emory University - Atlanta, GA

Master of Theological Studies
AUGUST 2013 - MAY 2015

Texas A&M University - College Station, TX

Bachelor of Arts in Philosophy AUGUST 2010 - AUGUST 2012